Briggs, Vernon, Files /4236
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Vernon Briggs Files
1959-2016
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Briggs, Vernon M.
/4236
17 cubic feet
17 linear ft.
Records (documents).
8056811
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 07, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019
Biographical / Historical
Vernon M. Briggs, Jr. is Emeritus Professor of Labor Economics, School of Industrial and Labor Relations, Cornell University. He received his B.S. degree in economics from the University of Maryland and his M.A. and Ph.D. degrees in economics from Michigan State University. Before coming to Cornell in 1978, he taught at the University of Texas at Austin for 14 years.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: /4236 PUBS: Vernon Briggs Publications
Briggs, Vernon M.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations
8056811
- Correspondence, 1963-1975. (Box 1)
  - Ph.D. Dissertation Letters, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Scope and Contents
    9/1/1964-8/31/1965
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    9/1/1965-8/31/1966
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    9/1/1966-8/31/1967
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    6/1/1967-6/1/1968
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    6/1/1968-5/31/1969
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    6/1/1969-5/31/1970
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence: Income, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    6/1/1970-5/31/1971
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    6/1/1971-5/31/1972
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    6/1/1972-5/31/1973
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    6/1/1973-5/31/1974
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    6/1/1974-12/31/1974
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    1/1/1975-5/31/1975
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    6/1/1974-5/31/1975
- Correspondence, 1975-1981. (Box 2)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    5/20/1975-12/30/1975
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    1/1/1976-5/31/1976
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1976-1977 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    12/19/1976-5/31/1977
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    6/1/1976
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    5/20/1975-5/30/1976
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    6/1/1976-12/15/1976
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    5/1/1977
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    5/31/1977-June
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    5/31/1977-11/30/1977
  - Correspondence: Outgoing (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    12/1/1977
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1977-1978 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    6/1/1977-8/1978
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Apprenticeship Confederation Sept. 1979
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    8-12/31/1978
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    6/1/1979-12/31/1979
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    1/1/1979-5/31/1979
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    June 1979 Apprenticeship Confederation
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    8/1978-6/1/1979
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    7/1-12/31/1980
  - Rural Studies Correspondence Incoming (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    1/1-6/30/1980
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    1/1-12/31/1980
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    1/1/1981-5/31/1981
  - Correspondence, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 25)
    6/1/1981-12/31/1981
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 26)
    1981
- Correspondence, 1982-1986. (Box 3)
  - General Correspondence: Incoming, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    1/1/1982-6/30/1982
  - General Correspondence: Outgoing, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence: Incoming, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    7/1/1982-12/31/1982
  - General Correspondence: Incoming, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    1/1/1983-6/30/1983
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    7/1/1983-12/31/1983
  - General Correspondence: Outgoing, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    1/1/1983-12/31/1983
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    1/1/1984-6/30/1984
  - Correspondence: Incoming - TVA Project, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing - TVA Project, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    1/1/1984-12/31/1984
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    6/1/1984-12/31/1984
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    7/1/1985-12/31/1985
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    1/1/1985-6/30/1985
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    1/1/1985-12/31/1985
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    1/1/1986-6/30/1986
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    6/15/1986-12/31/1986
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    1/1/1986-12/30/1986
- Correspondence (includes NCEP chairmanship), 1986-1990. (Box 4)
  - Correspondence: Incoming - NCEP, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing - NCEP, 1986 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    1/1-12/31/1987
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    1/1-6/30/1987
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1987 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    7/1-12/31/1987
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    1/1-6/30/1988
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    6/1-12/31/1988
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    1/1-12/31/1988
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    1-6/1989
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    5-12/1989
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    1/1/1990-
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    1/1/1990 -
- Correspondence, 1990-1993. (Box 5)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    7/1-12/31/1990
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    1/1/1991
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    1/1/1991-12/31/1991
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    1/1/1992-6/30/1992
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    7/1/1992-12/31/1992
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1992 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    1/1/1992 -
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    1/1/1993-6/30/1993
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    7/1/1993-12/31/1993
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1993 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    1/1/1993-12/31/1993
- Correspondence, 1994-1996. (Box 6)
  - AFEE Incoming, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    1/1/1994 -
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    1/1994 -
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    7/1/1994-12/31/1994
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    1-6/1995
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    6/15/1995-12/31/1995
  - AFEE Incoming, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - AFEE Outgoing, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    1/1/1996-6/30/1996
  - Correspondence: Incoming, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    6/30/1996-12/31/1996
  - Correspondence: Outgoing, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    1/1/1996-12/31/1996
- Articles and reprints by Vernon Briggs, 1965-2002. (Box 7)
  - 1. "Mutual Aid Pact - Airlines", 1965 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Industrial and Labor Review
  - 2. "The Strike. Insur. Plan of Railroad Industry", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Industrial Relations
  - 3. "Negro Apprentice Programs", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Journal of Human Resources
  - 4. "Remedies for Dis. In Apprentice Program", 1967 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - 5. "Labor in South: Manpower.. Programs and Regional Development", 1968 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Monthly Labor Review
  - 6. "A Review Article: Report of Committee on Civil Disorders", 1968 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Journal of Economic Issues
  - 7. "The Negro in American Industry: Review of Seven Studies", 1970 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    The Journal of Human Resources
  - 8. "National Manpower. Policy", 1971 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    The Encyclopedia of Education
  - 9. "Chicanos and Rural Poverty: A Cont. Issue for the 1970s", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    Poverty and Human Resources
  - 10. "The Federal Emergency Employment Act of 1971: The Texas Experience", 1972 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    The Emergency Employment Act: Interim Assessment
  - 11. "The Federal Emergency Employment Act of 1971: An Appraisal of Texas Experience", 1973 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    Public Affairs Comment
  - 12. "Mexica Immigration and Labor Market", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    Texas Business Review
  - 13. "Mexican Workers-U.S. Labor Market", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    International Labour Review
  - 14. "Illegal Aliens - Border Policy", 1975 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    Social Science Quarterly
  - 15. "Illegal Immigration - 'Soft' Data", 1976 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    American Behavioral Scientist
  - 16. "Railroad Brotherhoods", 1976 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    Dictionary of American History
  - 17. "Problem of Illegal Immigration", 1977 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - 18. "Issues-Full Employment Policy" (Box 7, Folder 18)
    Labor Law Journal
  - 19. "La Confronacion del Chicano", 1978 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    Foro Internacional
  - 20. "Welfare Reform and Plight of Poor", 1978 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - 21. "Wage, Occupational Difference - Black and White", 1978 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    Southern Economic Journal
  - 22. "Quest- Enforceable Immigration Policy", 1979 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    Trust: Journal for Employment and Training Professionals
  - 23. "Youth Employment Programs - Case Studies", 1980 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - 24. "Economic Development - Poverty Solution in Rural South", 1980 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    Growth and Change
  - 25. "Illegal Immigration - Cot. Issue for 1980s", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 25)
    The Bell Journal
  - 26. "Employment and Income Issues - SW 1980s", 1981 (Box 7, Folder 26)
    Adherent: A Journal of Comprehensive Employment and Human Resource Development
  - 27. "Report - Selection Committee on Immigration and Reform Policy", 1982 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - 28. "Illegal Immigration - Mexico and Labor Force Implications", 1983 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    ILR Report
  - 29. "Non-Immigration Labor Policy in the US", 1983 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - 30. "Methods of Analysis - Illegal Immigration", 1984 (Box 7, Folder 30)
    International Migration Review
  - 31. "Immigration Policy for Today", 1985 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    Business Forum
  - 32. "The Albatross - Temporary Work Policy", 1986 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - 33. "Immigration Reform's Unfinished Agenda", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 33)
    Human Resource Executive
  - 34. "Human Resource Development and Form. National Economic Policy", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - 35. "Youth Employment and Training Review", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    ILR Review
  - 36. "Growth and Composition - US Labor Force", 1987 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    Science
  - 37. "Efficiency and Equity - Goals of US Immigration", 1989 (Box 7, Folder 37)
    Population and Environment
  - 38. "Forum: Immigration Policy and Skill Shortages", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 38)
    BNA's Employee Weekly
  - 39. "Labor Market Transform: Role of US Immigration", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 39)
    Population and Environment Journal
  - 40. "Role of Public Policy in Rural Labor Market", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    Food and Life Sciences Quarterly
  - 41. "Immigration Policy and Workforce Prepared", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - 42. "Employer Sanctions and Question Discrimination", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - 43. "Comments: Findings and Policy Implications GAO Report", 1990 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - 44. "Changing Nature in Workforce", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    Looking Ahead
  - 45. "Immigration Reform and Urban Labor Force", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - 46. "Immigration Policy: Political/Economic?", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    Challenge: Magazine of Economic Affairs
  - 47. "Immigration Act of 1990: Retreat and Reform", 1991 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - 48. "Mexican Free Trade Agreement - Not Yet", 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    The Social Contract
  - 49. "Despair Behind Riots: Impediments to Mass Immigration", 1992 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    Scope
  - 50. "Policy Dilemmas - Urban Education and Needs of Poor", 1992 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    Journal of Urban Affairs
  - 51. "Memorial Session: Dudley Dillard", 1993 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - 52. "Dead-end Street: Female Immigration and Child Care", 1993 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    Child Care Action News
  - 53. "Immigration Labor and Issue - 'Dirty Work'", 1993 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - 54. "US Asylum Policy and New World Order", 1993 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    People and Place: Australian Forum
  - 55. "Administrating US Immigration Policy", 1994 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - 56. "Mass Immigration, Free Trade", 1995 (Box 7, Folder 56)
    Challenge May 1995
  - 57. "Mass Immigration Worsens Plight for the Urban Underclass", 1995 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    Forum for Applied Research
  - 58. "Immigration Policy and US Economy", 1996 (Box 7, Folder 58)
    June 1996
  - 59. "Ethics Trumping Economics?", 1997 (Box 7, Folder 59)
    The Social Contract Winter 1997
  - 60. "Error Discover in Unemployment Rate", 1998 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    Immigration Review Winter 1998
  - 61. "Malthus: The Economy", 1998 (Box 7, Folder 61)
    The Social Contract Spring 1998 (p. 206-15)
  - 62. "American Style Capitalism: The Challenge of Social Anarchy", 1998 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    Journal of Economic Issues June 1998
  - 63. "Henry George's Cont. to Political Economy", 1999 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    Encyclopedia of Political Economy Vol. 1 1999
  - 64. "US Immigration Policy and Plight of Unskilled Workers", 1999 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    Australian Forum for Population Studies Vol 7 1999
  - 65. "Rein-in A Rog. Policy: Imp. Of Immigration Reform", 1999 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    University of Miami Law Review Winter/Spring 1999
  - 66. "Immigration Policy and Human Resource Development", 1999 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    HR Spectrum July/August 1999
  - 67. "American Unionism and US Immigration Policy", 2001 (Box 7, Folder 67)
    Background Center for Immigration Studies August 2001
  - 68. "At a Crossroad: Immigration Reform and American Unionism" - The Social Contract Winter, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - 70. "Issues in Full Employment Policy" - IRRA, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - 71. "The Significance of Welfare Reform for the Rural South" - 13th Annual Meeting for the IRRA, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - 72. "The Revival of Job Creation Programs in the 1970s: Lessons for the 1980s" - 34th Annual Meeting for the IRRA, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - 73. "Immigration and Employment Discussion" - 36th Annual Meeting of the IRRA, 1984 (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - 74. "Immigration Reform and the Urban Labor Market: Resolved and Unresolved Data Issues" - 1988 Meeting of Am. Stat. Assoc., 1989 (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - 75. "Immigration Reform and Urban Labor Force" -1991 Meeting of IRRA (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - 76. "Introduction of 1993 Recipient of Veblen-Commons Award: Ray Marshall" - Journal of Economic Issues (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - 77. "Immigration: Neglected Orphan of Economic Policy" - Background 1993 Publication of CIS (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - 78. Unz. - Them: A Debate on Immigration Policy Review 1995 (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - 79. Immigration and Poverty Reduction - JEI Fall 2004 (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - 80. "Immigration: A Rogue Labor Market Policy" - Summer 2004 (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - 80. "Economic Well-Being of Black Americans" - Summer 2003 (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - 81. "Guest Worker Programs Lessons" - Background CIS March 2004 (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - 82. "Immigration Policy and American Unionism" - Future of Labor Unions 2004 (Box 7, Folder 82)
  - 83. "Economic Well-Being of Black Americans" - 2004 (Box 7, Folder 83)
- Publications: 1. Chapters in books, 1968-2000.; 2. Public testimonies, 1978-1995; 3. Special reports a. Emercency Employment Act (Texas), 1973; b. Youth Employment, 1980, 1968-2000. (Box 8)
  - Immigration in the National Interest Act of 1995: Hearing of Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Rep. on HR 1915 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Immigration Act of 1989 (Part 3) (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - The Economic Evolution of Rural America (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Legal Immigration Reforms (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Undocumented Workers: Implications for US Policy in the Western Hemisphere (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Immigration to the United States (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Impact of Illegal Immigration on Public Benefit Programs and the American Labor Force (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - The Knowing Employment of Illegal Immigrants (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Administration of Training Program - Compendium of Papers of Federal Program (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Texas: Emergency Employment Act 1974 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - The Employment and Inc. of Black Americans: Career Behavior of Sp. Groups 1975 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Illegal Immigrants and the American Labor Force - Current Issues in Social Policy 1976 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Labor Market Aspects of Mexican Migration Views Across the Border 1978 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Special Labor Market Segments - Manpower Research and Labor Economy 1979 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - La Migracion Como Un Fenomeno Socio Estudios Fronterizos 1981 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Unemployment and Underemployment - Nonmetropolitan America in Transition 1981 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - For. Labor Prog. As an Alternative to Illegal - The Border that Joins 1982 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Non-Immigrant Labor Policy: Future Trend. Or Aberration - The Unavoidable Issues: US Immigration Policy 1983 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Employment Trends and Contemporary Immigration Policy - Immigration: Issues and Policies 1985 (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Employment Trends and Contemporary Immigration Policy - Clamor at the Gates 1985 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Immigration Reform and US Employment Policy - In Defense of the Alien 1986 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - The Imperative Immigration Reform - Essays of Legal and Illegal Immigrants 1986 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Rural Labor Markets: The Role of Government Symposium on Rural Labor Market Issues 1986 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Human Resource Development and Formation of Economic Policy - Evolutionary Economy 1988 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - The Mexican Free Trade Agreement: In Defense of the Alien 1992 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Political Confrontation with Economic Real. - Elephants in the Volks Facing Questions 1992 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Mass Immigration, Free Trade, and the Forgotten Worker - In Defense of the Alien 1995 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - International Migration and Labor Mobility - The Economy of Labor Migration 1996 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Achieving National Economic and Social Goals of Heart and Mind - Social Political Essays in Honor of Levitan 1996 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Income Dispute and Unionism: Workplace Infl. Of Post '65 Immigration Policy - Inequality Paradox 1998 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Legal Immigration Policy for the 21st Century - Blueprints for an Ideal Legal Immigrant Policy 2001 (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Immigration Policy and the US Economy: An Institutional Approach - Race and Ethnicity in the US 2000 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Misc. Proceedings Lists (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Youth Knowledge Development Report - May 1980 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Youth Knowledge Development Report - May 1980 (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Youth Knowledge Development Report - May 1980 (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Case Studies of the Emergency Employment Act in Operation (Box 8, Folder 37)
- Correspondence, 1997-2000. (Box 9)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1/1997 - ) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (6/30-12/31/1997) (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence: Out (1/1/1997 - ) (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1-6/30/1998) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (6/15-12/31/1998) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: Out (1/1/1998 - ) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1-6/30/1999) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (7/1-12/31/1999) (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Out (1/1/1999-12/31/1999) (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (1/1-6/30-2000) (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence: Incoming (7/1-12/31/2000) (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence: Out (1/1-12/21/2000) (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Books and Monographs by Vernon Briggs. (Box 10)
  - Professional Vita Syllabus (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - The US Population and its Civilian Labor Force: Evolving Incongruity (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - "Immigration and American Unionism" - by Vernon Briggs, Jr. (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - "Mass Immigration and the National Interest" - Vernon Briggs, Jr. (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - "Immigration Policy: A Tool of Labor Economics?" (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - "Still an Open Door" - Vernon Briggs, Jr. (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - "Mass Immigration and the National Interest" -Vernon Briggs, Jr. (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - "Labor Economics: 6th Edition" (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - "Immigration: Issues and Policies" (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - "Public Service Employment in the Rural South" (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - "Labor Economics: 5th Edition" (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - "The Internationalization of the US Economy" (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "Apprenticeship Research Emerging Findings and Future Trends" (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - "The Population and Labor Force of NY: 1990-2050" (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - "Youth Employment Programs in the Southwest: Three Case Studies" (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Labor Economics (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - "Human Needs and Income Supplement Programs in the Rural South" (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - "Employment, Income, and Welfare in the Rural South" (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - "The Chicano Worker" (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - "Chicanos and Rural Poverty" (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - "Mexican Migration and the US Labor Market" (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - "The Mexico-US Border: Public Policy and Chicano Economic Welfare (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - "Negro Employment in the South" (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Houston Hearing, June 1970 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Equal Apprenticeship Opportunities (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - "The Negro and Apprenticeship" (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Preliminary reports, final reports and executive summaries of reports to United States Department of Labor of sponsored research; also, course syllabi for classes taught. (Box 11)
  - Book Reviews 1967-2004 - Vernon Briggs (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Course Syllabi - ILR 300 (Box 11, Folder 2)